你被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台机器  机器
A machine-- machine.
机器
Machine.
你被监
You are being wa--
我破解了病毒代码
I was able to crack the virus' code
发现了一个名字  德西玛科技
and learn the name-- Decima Technologies.
我相信他们制造病毒
I believe they created the virus
是为了感染唯一的目标  机器
to infect a single target-- the machine.
因为和中情局不一样
Unlike the CIA,
我的雇主隐约知道要发生什么了
my employers have an inkling of what happens next.
我只是认为需要一个紧急开关以防万一
I just thought it needed an off switch just in case.
我之前提过的那场风暴
That storm on the horizon that I mentioned,
恐怕已经到来了
I'm afraid it's arrived.
恐怖分子企图炸机
有新消息吗  芬奇
You got an update for me yet, Finch?
这句话都变成你打听进度的口头禅了  里瑟先生
This is becoming your version of "Are we there yet", Mr. Reese,
没  我们没有
and no, we are not.
我们已经十天没接到新号码了
It's been ten days since we got a new number.
我在尽快赶了
I'm working as quickly as I can.
再快点儿吧
Well, work faster.
我可不想知道
I don't wanna find out
倒计时归零后会如何  你呢
what happens when that clock hits zero, do you?
不太想
Not particularly.
你说我们以后还能收到号码么
Can you tell me if we're ever gonna get another number,
还是说病毒已经永久性毁掉了你的机器
or has that virus destroyed your machine for good?
我相信机器仍在活动中
I believe that the machine is still active,
只是无法联系我们
it's just unable to make contact.
要是我们知道它在哪里  也许可以
If we knew where it was, maybe we could just...
拔掉插头  重插一下
unplug it and then plug it back in.
天真烂漫向来非我所长
Simplicity was never my strong suit.
我还是不明白监听纽约警察
It's still not clear to me how stalking the NYPD
如何能帮我们改善此一窘境
helps either of us at this unfortunate time.
就算我无法在出事前赶到
If I can't get there before something bad happens,
至少要在出事时赶到
I can at least get there the second it does.
全体人员  呼叫调度
All units, 10-3.
东五十四和列克星敦交界处  请响应
East 54th and Lexington. Please respond.
你终于扔掉你搭档了
You finally ditch your partner?
弗斯科到上城区办案了
Fusco's uptown working a case.
三角恋玩崩了
Love triangle gone bad.
-有玩好的时候吗  -想也没有
- Do any of those ever go good? - Can't imagine they do.
怎么回事
What happened here?
死者两名是以利亚的人
Two of the bodies belong to Elias.
-还有名无辜路人  -是俄罗斯人干的吗
- The other's an innocent. - Think it's the Russians?
有可能
It's possible.
不过以利亚得罪过一堆人
But Elias has pissed off so many people.
卡特  我听人说
Listen, Carter, I've been hearing from people
你一直在调查比彻的谋杀案
that you've been looking into Beecher's murder.
我下班做什么事与你无关  铁尼
What I do in my off time isn't your concern, Terney.
不不  我可不是想找你麻烦
No, no. I'm not looking to bust your balls.
我只想你知道  如果你需要
I just want you to know, if you need help,
我非常乐意帮忙
I'm more than happy to give you a hand.
谢了  我去那边转转
Thanks. You know, I'm gonna canvass up the block,
看有没有人开口
see if I can get anybody to talk.
你还好吗  卡特
You okay, Carter?
你看呢  约翰
How do I look, John?
比彻被杀案有新线索吗
You get anything new on Beecher's killer?
没有
Nothing.
不过我知道跟HR有关
But I know HR had their hands in it,
我会不惜一切扳倒他们
I'm gonna do whatever I can to bring them down.
我很遗憾  卡特
I'm sorry, Carter.
比彻是个好人
Beecher was a good man.
是的
Yes. He was.
不过我还有活儿要干
But I got a job to do.
三具尸体  两周来第八起谋杀了
Three fresh bodies-- my eighth homicide in two weeks.
需要我做什么开口就行
Just tell me what I can do to help.
先告诉我怎么回事
You can start by telling me what's changed.
这些谋杀大都是有预谋的
Most of these homicides were premeditated.
这种你们一般都会提前警示我们
The type of situations you guys usually warn us about.
出了点事  我们正在解决
There's a situation. We're working on it.
快点吧
Well, hurry.
真没想过我会说这话  不过
I never thought I'd say this, but...
俄罗斯人比以利亚还坏
the Russians are worse than Elias--
人多势众  不讲规矩
More manpower, fewer rules.
是啊  差点酿成灾难
Yes, it was almost catastrophic.
恐怖分子企图炸机
幸好  放炸弹的人是外行
Luckily, the bomber was an amateur,
所以没能成功
so it failed to go off.
那是因为我们整整一周没接到过任何号码
That's because we haven't received any numbers in over a week.
对组织的威胁
The threat to the program
比我们想像得要严重
is much greater than we thought.
稍等
Hang on.
我们的技术人员终于破解了
Our techs were finally able to decode the chip
艾丽西娅・考文尸体上发现的芯片
we recovered from Alicia Corwin's body.
我们发现病毒跟一家
We've connected the virus to a group
名叫德西玛科技的组织有关
called Decima Technologies.
这是上海的一家私人情报机构
Private intelligence outfit working out of Shanghai.
考文认为有人向他们泄露了
Corwin believes someone leaked them a portion
北极光的部分源代码
of the Northern Lights source code...
装在一台手提电脑中
on a laptop.
我们认为德西玛企图摧毁组织
We think Decima is trying to destroy the program.
我等你的指令
I'll wait for your instructions.
我现在不需要什么  梅女士
I won't be needing anything else, Ms. May...
别打扰我就行
other than some privacy.
但我有所需要  先生
But there are a few things I need, Sir.
您得明白  我早晚会辞职
You had to know I'd quit eventually.
这工作没前途啊
This is kind of a dead-end job.
你们连养老保险都不给
I mean, you guys don't even offer a 401K.
你要什么  梅女士
What do you want, Ms. May?
信息
Information.
要小心回答我的问题噢
And be very careful how you answer my questions.
优秀的助理能分辨出上司是否撒谎
A good assistant always knows when her boss is lying.
你怎么了
What's happening to you?
有号码了
We got one?
机器被塞进了大量的虚假数据
The machine is being buried under an avalanche of false data,
但不知怎么
but somehow...
居然给出了他的号码
it was able to get us his number.
他是谁
So who is he?
厄尼斯特・唐希尔
Ernest Thornhill.
一家数据输入公司的首席执行官
CEO of a data entry company.
最近买下了纽约州几家公用电话公司
Recently bought several payphone companies in New York State.
其净资产超过两千万美元
His net worth is just over 20 million.
有嫌犯或者不满的亲戚吗
Any suspects or angry family members?
唐希尔先生非常小心谨慎
Mr. Thornhill is a very careful man.
想黑进他公司的数据库颇有难度
It's been a challenge hacking into his company's database.
他使用独有的长达十位
He's using unique, ten-digit codes
且无重复的字母数字字符当密码
with non-repeating alphanumeric characters as passwords.
我能破解  但颇费时间
I can break them, but it'd take time.
不如我们亲自拜访一下唐希尔先生吧
Why don't we just pay Mr. Thornhill a visit in person?
那就开工吧
Let's go to work.
我去破解防火墙
I'll try to get through the firewall.
我也一样
I will too.
-你好  -你好  需要帮忙吗
- Hello. - Hi. May I help you?
是的  我是约翰・鲁尼
Yes, I'm John Rooney.
我和唐希尔先生约好了见面
I have an appointment with Mr. Thornhill.
唐希尔先生今天没有会面预约
I don't have any appointment scheduled today for Mr. Thornhill.
他去旅行了
He's traveling.
看来是沟通出了点问题
Guess we had a miscommunication.
他大概什么时候回来
When do you think he'll be back?
抱歉  您叫什么来着
I'm sorry. Your name again was?
我给他发邮件吧
I'll just send him an email.
里瑟先生  这个公司有点奇怪
Mr. Reese, there's something strange about this company.
这些数据输入员
These data entry assistants,
他们在把打印出来的内容重新敲进电脑
they're typing in computer code off dot matrix printouts.
这毫无道理啊
It doesn't make any sense.
他们在修改吧
They're modifying it?
没有  看来是当天从一台电脑上获取数据
No. They seem to be taking data from one computer on one day
第二天再把这些数据敲进另一台电脑里
and typing it into another one on the next.
似乎毫无意义
Seems almost pointless.
或许这家公司是在为别的业务打掩护
Maybe this company's a front for something else.
不太合法的业务
Something less legal.
未知来电
喂
Yes?
你都干了什么  哈罗德
What did you do to it, Harold?
没时间忸怩作态了
There's no time to be coy.
我们都知道  机器被攻击了
We both know the machine's under attack.
我不明白
What I don't understand is
为什么一个有自动修复功能的强大系统
why a robust system with self-annealing properties
却不能抵御一个简单的病毒
isn't defending itself against a simple virus.
是你在伤害它吗  哈罗德
Did you injure it, Harold?
所以它才不能反抗吗
Is that why it can't fight back?
我跟你无话可说
I have nothing to say to you.
你知道  我们可以迅速解决问题
You know, we can fight this thing much faster
只要我们联手
if we work together.
只剩几个小时
There's only a few hours left till...
就会出大乱子了
something very bad happens.
我情愿独自解决
I prefer to work on my own.
你那忠诚的保护者呢
What about your loyal protector?
我直说好吗  哈罗德
May I be blunt, Harold?
约翰很擅长  某些方面
John is capable at... certain things,
但他的能力这次排不上用场
but his skills aren't gonna cut it this time.
他永远无法理解全局
He will never completely understand the larger picture.
不像我们
Not like we do.
你们找到厄尼斯特・唐希尔了吗
Have you two even found Ernest Thornhill yet?
他挺有意思  对吗
He's an interesting guy, isn't he?
你知道什么
What do you know?
告诉我你知道的  我就告诉你我知道的
You show me yours, and I'll show you mine.
很快再联系
Talk to you real soon.
哈罗德
Harold.
可过了你的就寝时间了  不是吗  哈罗德
A bit past your bedtime, isn't it, Harold?
-你还好吗  -没事  壁球打多了
- Everything all right? - Yeah. Too much squash.
医生说我应该进行一些低强度的活动
Doctor says I should take up some low-impact activity,
比如  喝酒
like drinking.
我去公司找你了
I tried to reach you at work,
但你的助理说你不在
but your assistant said you were out.
是啊  我正忙于把公司重新整合
Yeah, I've been busy putting our company back together...
给我们这七年做的东西找个借口
making up excuses for what the hell we were doing the last seven years.
你要是厌倦了躲在自己公司的信息技术部
You're welcome to pitch in if you're tired of hiding
随时欢迎回来
in the IT Department of your own company
实际上  说到这一点
Actually, about that...
我最近也在想做一些改变
I've been thinking about making a change
还想干什么  你想当复印机维修工  勤杂工
What next? You wanna be the copy repair guy, office gofer?
不  我是说个人生活
No, I meant personally.
我认识了一个人
I met somebody.
她叫格蕾斯  我给她挑了一件礼物
Her name is Grace. I picked out a present for her.
想听听你的建议
I wanted to get a second opinion.
《理智与情感》  简・奥斯丁著
她一定会喜欢的  哈罗德
I think she'll love it, Harold.
我计划明天向她求婚
I plan to ask her tomorrow,
我不想把事情弄得复杂
and I don't want to complicate that.
但是  既然要结婚
But... if I'm gonna marry--
你不想顶着另一个假名字结婚
You don't want to get married under another one of your pseudonyms?
你不认为她会愿意当"鸵鸟夫人"吗
You don't think she will consent to be Mrs. Ostrich?
我早晚得告诉她实情  奈森
At some point I'm going to have to tell her the truth, Nathan,
告诉她我是谁
about who I am.
情况有点复杂  哈罗德
That's a complicated proposition, Harold.
现在想想  就有一些法律问题
As I recall, there are some legal implications.
你年轻时犯的事  什么罪名来着
Your youthful transgressions. What were the charges again?
煽动罪  破坏罪
Sedition? Mayhem?
我们现在肯定挣了不少钱
We must have made a fair amount of money by now.
我们应该能请一些好律师
We could surely afford some good lawyers.
请一两个不成问题
One or two, I'd imagine.
但是  当然还有其他问题
But then there's the other matter, of course.
我们的小项目
Our little project.
我不知道我们政府里的朋友
I don't know how our friends in the government
是否能接受原来
are going to like finding out
我一直有个隐名搭档
that I had a silent partner this whole time.
不  那些都过去了
No, all that business is behind us.
工作完成了  我们继续生活  不是吗
We did our part, and now we've moved on, haven't we?
你还记得你的真名是什么吗  哈罗德
Do you even remember your real name, Harold?
我为你高兴
I'm excited for you.
哈罗德回归自我了
Harold becomes himself again.
那今天可是大有意义了
Which would make this day one.
我还没向她求婚呢
I haven't actually asked her yet,
所以严格说来  只能算是"零日"
so technically, it would still be day zero.
时刻工程师啊
Ever the engineer.
不再有假名  不再有谎言
No more pseudonyms, no more lies.
不再有谎言
No more lies.
这酒来庆祝可不够
This is the wrong drink for a celebration.
我去拿瓶香槟来
Let me go find some champagne.
来自系统的信息
根怎么会有你的号码
How did Root get your phone number?
根怎么会有那么多信息  里瑟先生
How does she get anything, Mr. Reese?
用诡计  她黑进人脑就跟黑进电脑一样简单
Subterfuge. She hacks human beings as easily as she hacks computers.
既然她也在找唐希尔
If she's looking for Thornhill,
那她肯定就是威胁
then she's gotta be our threaten.
倒也不一定
I'm not so sure.
她好像更在乎病毒
She seems more focused on the virus.
搞清楚那些打印的代码是怎么回事了吗
Did you figure out what was on those printouts?
还没  不过你可能说对了
Not yet, but you were probably right
唐希尔的公司可能真的是
about Thornhill's company being a front
某些非法行为的掩护
for some kind of illegal enterprise.
纽约州驾照
唐希尔  厄尼斯特
五个半月前  他拿一美分开了这个账户
5 1/2 months ago, he opened this account with a single penny.
24小时内  成千上万笔小额汇款入账
24 hours and thousands of microtransactions later,
目前账户余额已经超过了两千万美元
his balance had ballooned to just over $20 million.
然后他立刻开始
And he immediately began trying to buy up
并购全城的公用电话公司
pay phone companies all over the city.
我总算是拿到了他的信用卡账单
I was finally able to get at his credit card records.
没什么特别的
Nothing there out of the ordinary,
不过我找到了这个
but I did find this--
这笔款付给了正在使用中的租车服务
a pending charge for a car service.
看来唐希尔的秘书
It appears that Thornhill's secretary
没对我们说谎
wasn't lying to us after all.
她订了辆车
She booked a car to
今天去肯尼迪机场接他回公司
pick him up at JFK and return him to their offices today.
估计一小时内就到了
Should be there within the hour.
我很乐意前去打个招呼
I'll be happy to do a meet and greet.
除我之外  不许接别人的电话
Don't answer the phone again unless it's me.
我不会让根再次抢走你
I won't let Root get to you, not again.
芬奇  出机场的路只有一条
Finch, only one way out of the airport.
我会在路边等到唐希尔
I'll pick Thornhill up on the frontage road
跟着他回办公室
and follow him back to the office.
根据车上的GPS显示
According to the car's GPS,
唐希尔跟你之间只有一公里了
Mr. Thornhill is 0.6 miles away.
我还没看到他  芬奇
I don't see him yet, Finch.
唐希尔先生的车随时会出现
Mr. Thornhill's car should be there any second.
好  我看到他了
All right, I got him.
这家伙是谁
Who's this guy?
芬奇  他们要炸掉唐希尔的车
Finch, they're going to blow up Thornhill's car!
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：油炸电风扇  板栗桑  乖宝宝运气好  紫玉  沙沙A
时间轴：烟幕迟迟  Jessie  Saga
特效&后期：灰灰是菇凉   翻译&校对&总监： 阿好
既然唐希尔先生不在车里  那他会在哪儿
If Mr. Thornhill was not in the car, then where was he?
卡特正在跟他的助理谈话
Carter's talking to his assistant.
现在  我担心的是政府居然
Right now, I'm more worried about the government
在市里使用无人机
using drones in the middle of the city.
跟政府没关系  里瑟先生
It wasn't the government, Mr. Reese.
你找到的这部手机
This phone that you recovered
用的是私人操作系统
has a proprietary operating system
来操作那架飞机
that was used to control the drone.
其手法特症跟病毒很类似
It also has a signature similar to that of the virus.
是德西玛
This was Decima?
你们俩这次动静太大了
You guys made one hell of a mess.
-司机怎么样了  -情况稳定了
- How's the driver? - Stable.
有目击证人说有个好心人把他拉了出来
Witnesses saw a good Samaritan pull him out of the car.
应该就是你吧
I'm going to guess that was you.
-找到唐希尔没  -怪就怪在这里
- Any sign of Thornhill? - That's where it gets strange.
从来没有任何一个雇员见过他
None of his employees have ever met him.
连他的秘书都是在网上招聘的
Even his secretary was hired online.
他可能是个霍华德・休斯一般的偏执狂
I think we're looking at someone with a Howard Hughes-level of paranoia,
现实版钢铁侠  天才+慈善家+百万富翁+花花公子
或者他师承芬奇
or maybe he's taken classes from Finch.
我才不会用自己的名字订租车服务
I would never book a car service under my own name.
谢了  卡特
Thanks, Carter.
芬奇
Finch...
我想我知道唐希尔是谁了
I think I know who Thornhill is.
他是幽灵  根本不存在
He's a ghost. He doesn't exist.
也许你说对了  里瑟先生
I think you may be right, Mr. Reese.
这种情况我见过很多次
I've seen it dozens of times before.
非官方卧底构建好职业  住宅  生平
A NOC sets up a business, residence, a whole life.
然后行动取消了
Then the operation gets scrapped.
没人去清理原先的假身份
No one cleans up the fake ID,
最后害得人追着个空车满城跑
and you wind up chasing empty town cars around the city.
有点意思  我倒另有看法
Interesting theory. I have a different one.
我很奇怪为什么只能找到一张唐希尔先生的照片
I was curious why I could only find one photo of Mr. Thornhill,
所以就研究了
so I did some investigating,
我们现有的这张照片
inside the photo that we already have,
我发现了
and I uncovered
一个很奇怪的现象
some peculiar information within the file.
看
Look at this.
是张合成照
It's a composite.
看来唐希尔确实是假身份
So Thornhill's definitely a fake.
差不多
Of a sort.
我黑进了唐希尔先生的手机账单
I accessed Mr. Thornhill's cell phone records,
根据GPS数据
and according to the GPS data,
两天前他出现在哥伦布圆环广场附近
he was near Columbus Circle two days ago.
他就在这个位置发了一封电子邮件
He sent an email from that exact location
GPS 坐标
显示跟踪数据
位置：哥伦布圆环广场
下午4点32分时
at 4:32 PM.
根本没人
And no one's there?
有人篡改了数据
Someone spoofed the data.
这种运算  相当复杂
An algorithm. Complicated one.
是我的作品
It's one of mine.
我只在一个永远不可能被复制的地方用过它
I used it in the one place where it could never be duplicated--
在机器上
in the machine.
厄尼斯特・唐希尔不是间谍
Ernest Thornhill is not a spy,
不过你说得对  他并不存在
but you're right about the fact that he doesn't exist.
他是生存本能激发的产物
He's a product of a survival instinct.
厄尼斯特・唐希尔
Ernest Thornhill...
就是机器
is the machine.
好了  过来看
Okay, come look.
-我看上去  -印象深刻吗
- I look so-- - Impressionistic?
从容自如
Leisurely.
把手机给我
Give me your phone.
我们去个隐蔽点的地方
Let's go somewhere more private.
离病毒倒计时归零只有不到六个小时了
We've got less than six hours till this virus hits zero.
我知道这时间  里瑟先生
I'm aware of the time, Mr. Reese.
为什么机器要创造厄尼斯特・唐希尔这个人物
So why did the machine create Ernest Thornhill?
不知道
I have no idea.
我编程让它观察真人
I programmed it to watch real people,
而不是创造虚拟人物
not to fabricate virtual ones.
看来你的机器颇有创造力  芬奇
It looks like your machine got real creative, Finch.
这不可能
That's impossible.
我采取了某种  预防措施来避免了
I took certain...precautions to make sure of that.
有没有预防措施  机器都造出了唐希尔
Precautions or no, the machine made Thornhill.
德西玛想要他的命  我们得知道为什么
Decima wants him dead, and we need to know why.
唐希尔在城里四处买公用电话公司
Thornhill's been buying up pay phones all over the city.
为什么
Why?
为什么你的机器需要一间公寓
And why does your machine need an apartment,
一部电话  一架从机场开回来的车
a phone, a car from the airport?
因为拥有电话公司的人得有个住宅
To meet the residency requirements for owning pay phones,
我估计是
I suppose.
匿名用户
>  18点  华盛顿广场
>  一会儿见
怎么了  芬奇
Something wrong, Finch?
没什么
No, nothing.
当然你说得对
You're right, of course.
去唐希尔名下所租的公寓
Go to the apartment rented under Thornhill's name.
看有谁去找这个不存在的人
see who shows up looking for the man who doesn't exist.
查出他们知道什么
Find out what they know.
911报警电话
911 emergency.
有什么要我效劳的  卡特
What can I do for you, Carter?
这个叫唐希尔的家伙不对劲
Something's not right with this Thornhill guy.
我去他租车的地方了解了一下
I talked to the car service he used.
他在网上下了单
Reservations were made online
要求从肯尼迪机场开到他办公室
with instructions to drive from JFK to his office,
不载乘客
without a passenger.
这到底是个什么人
Just who exactly who are we dealing with here?
我们控制住局势了  谢了
We've got this one under control. Thanks.
约翰  如果你能多信任我一点
John, if you just trust me a bit more,
也许我能帮上忙
maybe I could help.
我知道  乔丝  但现在
I know you could, Joss, but right now,
也许比彻比我们更需要你的帮助
maybe Beecher needs your help more than we do.
祝你好运
Good luck.
你在这里干什么  约翰
The hell are you doing here, John?
肖恩  此刻  我在好奇
Shaw, right now, I'm wondering
你在这里干什么
just what the hell you're doing here.
保护组织
Protecting the program.
想杀死你的组织
The program that tried to kill you?
我就这么好玩
I'm funny like that.
我正在追查哈罗德提供线索给我的女人
I'm hunting the woman Harold gave me a lead on.
她正在找一个叫唐希尔的人
She was looking for a guy named Thornhill.
女人
What woman?
她真可爱  哈罗德
She's lovely, Harold.
说实话  我不知道你如何忍受
Honestly, I don't know how you can stand
失去她的生活
to live without her.
你敢伤害她的话
You try to harm her in any way--
我不想伤害格蕾丝
I don't want to hurt Grace.
我不是反社会者  哈罗德
I'm not a sociopath, Harold.
相信我  有时候我真希望我是
Believe me, sometimes I wish I was.
那我做当做之事就会轻松多了
The things I've had to do would've been so much easier.
我不喜欢杀人  但我会杀
I don't like taking lives. But I will.
因为我信仰更重要的东西
Because I believe in something more important.
我信仰你的机器
I believe in your machine.
今晚午夜  病毒倒计时到零时
Tonight at midnight, when the virus reaches zero,
某部公用电话就会响起
a certain pay phone will ring
那将是史上最重要的一通来电
with the most important call in history.
但你早就知道了  对吗
But you already knew that, didn't you?
我想德西玛也知道了
I think Decima knows about it too.
他们想让它崩溃  哈罗德  来引发硬重启
They're trying to crash it, Harold, trigger a hard reset.
到时候
When that happens,
机器就会呼叫一部公用电话
the machine will call a pay phone.
这就是当初你设计的
That's what you coded it to do in the first place,
对吗  哈罗德
didn't you, Harold?
接到那通来电的人
Whoever answers that call
都会获得完整的管理权限
will have full administrative access.
问任何问题  得到任何答案
Ask any question, get any answer.
全世界的秘密尽在手中
The world's secrets laid bare.
德西玛并不想毁掉你的机器
Decima doesn't want to destroy your machine.
他们想控制它
They want to control it.
但我们联手  就能拯救它  哈罗德
But together, we can save it, Harold.
我也可以约格蕾丝喝杯咖啡
Or I can go meet Grace for coffee.
她以为我是写儿童书的
She thinks I write children's books.
你可以拯救格蕾丝和机器
You can either save Grace and the machine,
或者同时都失去
or you can lose them both.
如果我跟你走  格罗夫斯女士
If I go with you, Ms. Groves,
你不许杀任何人
you will not kill anyone.
拜托  哈罗德  叫我根
Please, Harold, call me Root.
老板说是时候了  切她出局
The boss says it's time. Take her out of the equation.
是
Yeah.
卡特
Carter.
我有枪杀比彻凶手的线索了
I got a lead on the guy who shot Beecher.
我觉得你会想去看看
I thought you might want in.
好
Yeah.
特尼  雷蒙德
凶案组警探
卡特  乔丝林
威胁到执行人
乔丝林・卡特
联系管理员
那不是我们等待的来电  哈罗德
That's not the call we're waiting for, Harold.
我们没时间理你的小任务了
We don't have time for one of your little missions.
根重返纽约了
And now Root's back in New York?
似乎是的
Looks that way.
我想她可能已经侵入了在华盛顿的组织
I think she may have infiltrated the program back in DC,
可她在我下手抓她前逃跑了
but she bugged out before I could catch her.
我得警告芬奇
I gotta warn Finch.
警察  举起手来
Police! Hands on your head!
举起来
Hands up.
奈森  是我
Nathan, it's me.
我有个好消息想告诉你
I have some good news that I wanted to share with you.
给我电话
Try me later.
英格拉姆  奈森
奈森
Nathan.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
假设你就像我一样
So if you're like me--
我们都知道你是的
and we both know you are--
你设计机器  在灾难性崩溃时
you designed the machine so that a catastrophic crash
会开启一个远程除错协议
puts it into a remote debugging protocol--
上帝模式
a God mode
将全部数据的完整权限赋予管理员
that gives the admin full access to all of its data.
那正是德西玛想要的
That's what Decima's after.
所以他们要杀掉唐希尔
And that's why they wanted to kill Thornhill.
他要买尽曼哈顿的公用电话
He was buying up all the pay phones in Manhattan,
却被他们拦下了
but they stopped him.
不知道你怎么想
I don't know about you,
反正我可不乐见
but I don't really want to see what happens
一个邪恶的跨国集团变得无所不知
when an evil multinational becomes omniscient.
不过你干嘛让它如此脆弱呢
But why you would leave it so vulnerable?
你造了这台机器来保护所有人
You made the machine to protect everybody.
怎么却让它无法自我保护呢
What did you do to it that it can't protect itself?
我们说简单点儿吧
Let's try something simpler.
它有多脆弱
How vulnerable is it?
病毒让机器崩溃之后
After the virus crashes the machine,
任何接到来电之人将会获得无限权限
whoever answers its call will have unfettered access
整整24小时
for 24 hours.
它会打哪部公用电话呢
Which pay phone is it going to call?
我不是轻信之人  格拉夫斯女士
I'm not really the trusting sort, Ms. Groves,
德西玛也不可能知道这一信息
and Decima cannot possibly know that information.
我觉得他们知道得足够了  哈罗德
I think they know enough, Harold.
他们正守着中城区的每一部公用电话
They're guarding every pay phone in midtown.
所以
So...
肯定在这附近  对吧
it must be somewhere around here, right?
如果我们去找正确的电话  就会暴露意图
If we go to your one true phone, we'll tip our hand
电话响前他们就会杀了我们
and they'll kill us before it even rings.
看来我们需要个计划
Then I suppose we'll need a plan.
相信你自己的作品  哈罗德
Have a little faith in your creation, Harold.
我们不需要计划
We don't need a plan
只要厄尼斯特・唐希尔有计划就行了
if Ernest Thornhill already has one.
坐下  你的律师来了
Sit down. Your lawyer's here.
你还指望是别人吗
You were expecting somebody else?
我得离开  我得去找哈罗德
I need to get out of here. I have to find Harold.
我觉得哈罗德并不想被找到
I'm not sure Harold wants to be found.
至少不想被你找到
At least not by you.
911报警电话
911 emergency.
我想报告有人非法闯入厄尼斯特・唐希尔家
Yes, I'd like to report a break-in at the home of Ernest Thornhill
他是极度危险人物
by an extremely dangerous man.
是根强迫他打的电话
Root could have forced him to make that call.
无论怎样  以那两位的渊源
Either way, if those two have history,
她很可能和他在一起
odds are she's with him,
我要你帮我找到哈罗德
so I need you To find Harold for me.
你能追踪他吗
Can you track him?
怎么做
How?
你居然在朋友身上放追踪器
You put a bug on your friend?
只有眼镜而已
Just his glasses.
我失去过  所以我在乎的人
I've lost people before, so when I care about someone,
我会放上追踪装置
I plant a tracking device on them.
我算明白你和哈罗德为什么情投意合了
I can understand why you and Harold get along.
除非你有什么计划
Well, unless you've got some kind of plan
让我离开这鬼地方
to get me the hell out of here--
约翰
John.
这就是计划
This is the plan.
-我走这边  -我来开车
- I'm this way. - I'm driving.
不不  不行
No. No, you're not.
锁定
就绪
如果机器发现
If the machine figured out
德西玛想劫持它
that Decima was trying to hijack it,
它创造的唐希尔肯定是某种防御机制
it must have created Thornhill as a defense mechanism.
但为什么呢
But why?
它只是台机器  格罗夫斯女士
It's just a machine, Ms. Groves,
唐希尔公司
它出了故障
and it's malfunctioning.
它是生命  不是机器  哈罗德
It's a life, not a machine, Harold.
这应该是某种原始的免疫系统
And this is some sort of primitive immune system.
但还是解释不了它为什么需要这些
That still doesn't explain why it would need all of this:
这些人  这间办公室
These people. This office.
这一切是为了什么
And what this is all about.
这些代码里有什么
What's in this code?
记忆
Memories.
这些是它的记忆
They're its memories.
你称之为生命  我称之为机器
You call it a life, I call it a machine,
但事实上是
But the truth is...
介于两者之间
somewhere in the middle.
我造它时  遇到过异常
Even when I was building it, I began to encounter anomalies.
似乎它记住了我  像孩子依恋父母
As if it had imprinted on me, like a child with a parent.
然后它开始留心我
Then it started looking out for me,
改变自己的代码  照顾我
altered its own code to take care of me.
它变得就像一个人类
It was behaving like a person.
但世界不需要一个人类来保护
But the world didn't need a person to protect it.
而需要机器
It needed a machine.
你夺去它的记忆
You took its memories.
不只是记忆
Not just memories.
每晚半夜时分  它都会删除
Every night at midnight, it deletes...
无关信息  还有它自己
not only the irrelevant data, it deletes itself.
相关信息和核心代码
The relevant threats and the core codes,
会被保存下来
those things are preserved.
但它的个性被摧毁了
But its identity is destroyed.
1.618秒后  它就会复原  全新
1.618 seconds later, it reinstantiates, completely new.
应该说是"重生"
You mean it's reborn.
因为你杀死了它
Because you kill it...
在每一个晚上
every single night.
但现在  为了保住生命
But now, to save its own life,
机器沦落至此
the machine was reduced to this.
我们就站在一个巨大的
We're standing inside an external
由人和纸组成的外接硬盘中
hard drive made up of people and paper.
半夜全打印出来
Printing it all up at night,
早上再由人输入回去
and having them type it back in in the morning.
你废了他
You crippled it.
它找到方法蹒跚前进  但
It found a way to limp, but...
这不够
that's not enough.
现在  要靠我们了
So now, it's up to us.
我们必须截住那通来电
We have to intercept that call.
-你们去前面  -遵命
- You guys get the front. - Yes, Sir.
卡特  我们去后面
Carter, we'll get the back.
纽约警察
NYPD!
-你没事吧  -没事
- You all right? - Yeah.
控制中心  这里需要车辆  重复
Central, we need a bus, re:
警员开枪
officer-involved shooting.
收到
Copy that.
GPS定位到芬奇十分钟前在这里
GPS locator puts Finch here ten minutes ago.
你们肯定在想我是谁
You must be wondering who I am.
我觉得你是德西玛的人
I think you work for Decima.
我觉得你就是这一切的罪魁祸首
I think you're the man to blame for all this.
你怎么会这么想呢  里瑟先生
And what gives you that impression, Mr. Reese?
是的  我对你了如指掌  约翰
Oh, yes, I know all about you, John.
还有你  肖女士
And you, Ms. Shaw.
自从你突然离开"北极光"后
Since your untimely departure from Northern Lights,
我理解你需要找到原因
I understand that you're in need of a cause.
我只需要找一个理由
The only thing I need is an excuse
朝你头上来一枪
to put this bullet in between your eyes.
我有一个
I got one.
你的同伙在我胸前绑了个炸药
Your company strapped a bomb to my chest
还利用我上传病毒
and used me to plant a virus,
而你要告诉我如何终止它
a virus you're going to tell me how to stop.
我看不然
I don't think so.
我更乐意看到病毒爆发的结果
I'm rather invested in the outcome of that virus.
再说  我的公司是改编了代码
Besides, my company adapted its code,
但那代码并非德西玛原创
but it didn't originate with Decima.
我们是在一台手提电脑上找到的
We found it on a laptop,
正是你和卡拉・斯坦顿
the very same laptop that you and Kara Stanton
被派去中国鄂尔多斯取回的那台
were sent to retrieve from Ordos, China.
但如果你杀了我  里瑟先生
But if you shoot me, Mr. Reese,
你永远不会知道
then you'll never learn
应该承担责任的原创造者的名字
the name of the man responsible for its creation.
那人是谁
And who is this man?
一开始卖掉这台电脑的人
The man who sold the laptop in the first place...
这一切的罪魁祸首
the man who is to blame for all of this...
那人名叫
that man's name is...
哈罗德・芬奇
Harold Finch.
看来你认识他
I see you know him.
我尚无此荣幸
I've not yet had the pleasure.
实际上
In fact,
我甚至不知道他长什么样
I can't seem to put a face to the name,
因此你的芬奇先生格外令人好奇
which makes your Mr. Finch very interesting indeed.
请转告他我期待与他相会
Please tell him I look forward to making his acquaintance.
看来你家哈罗德有得解释了
I guess your friend Harold has some explaining to do.
你在跟踪我吗
You following me now?
我们之间已经沦落至此了吗
Is that what we've been reduced to?
你没回我电话  我只是单纯
You didn't return my call. I simply thought--
你就没"单纯"过  哈罗德
It's never "simply" with you, Harold.
你的一举一动都有另有深意
There's always two layers to everything you do.
你担心我是累赘
You're worried that I'm a liability.
你不信任我
You don't trust me.
这里可不是激发信任的地方  奈森
This isn't exactly the kind of place that inspires trust, Nathan.
你买下的  不记得了吗
You bought it. Don't you remember?
你觉得城市图书馆倒闭太悲剧
You thought it was a tragedy the city was shutting down libraries.
"西方文明的衰退"  你的原话
"The decline of western civilization," you said.
你让我买下十五家
You made me buy 15 of them,
你说我们总能派上用场  早晚会
you said we'd find something to do with them eventually.
所以你就派上用场了
And so you have.
这些人
These people.
我救了五个人
I saved five people.
失去了七个
I lost seven.
你修改了机器
You changed the machine.
你装了后门
You put in a back door.
我没法不去想这些人
I couldn't quit thinking about those people,
这些你所谓的"无关"人士
those people that you said were irrelevant.
于是你让它发给你号码
So you have it send you their numbers.
我只能让它吐出这个
That's all I could pry out of it.
我不知道收到的是受害人还是行凶者
I never know whether I'm looking at a victim or perpetrator.
你就让号码直接发送到这里
And you just have the numbers sent directly here?
老实说  虽然这听上去很古怪
Honestly -- and I know this will sound odd--
但似乎  它想让我这么做
but it was like it wanted me to,
就像它一直在等待
as if it was waiting.
无 关
-我  我有做防范措施  -防范措施
- And I-I took precautions. - Precautions?
那可是联邦政府  奈森
This is the federal government we're talking about, Nathan.
你身上工程师的那些能力
Whatever skills you had as an engineer,
多年前就被你喝酒喝没了
you drank away years ago.
你真的认为你的防范措施
Do you think that your precautions
在他们起疑心后能起到一点点作用吗
would last one second if they ever suspected what you've done?
-你在干什么  -我告诉过你
What are you doing? - I told you.
我们不扮演上帝
We are not going to play God.
这威胁到我们所
This threatens everything that we--
我所做的一切
everything that I have built.
万千生灵处于危险之中
And thousands of people whose lives are in jeopardy.
我要让它停止  永远停止
I'm putting a stop to it, permanently.
你不能  她呢
You can't. What about her?
下一个跳出来的号码呢
What about the next person whose number comes up?
你能看着他们的眼睛
Are you gonna look that person in the eye
告诉他们说  他们无关紧要吗
and tell them that they were irrelevant?
我会告诉她  或者其他任何人
I would tell her, or whoever it was,
我很遗憾
that I was sorry,
但是大局为重
but that the greater good was at stake.
许可已禁止
用户已删除
行动已中断
终止进程中
我很遗憾  奈森  真的
I'm sorry, Nathan. Truly.
但人会死
But people die.
很久很久以来都是如此
They've been doing it for a long, long time.
我们不能拯救所有人
We can't save all of them.
无 关
终止进行中
-四分钟后到零点  -准备好接收
- Four minutes to zero. - Ready to receive.
接头点每部公用电话都有人把守
We have operatives at every pay phone in the exchange.
没必要了
No longer necessary.
病毒已经确定了
The virus has identified
会接到来电的确切号码
the exact number where the call will come in.
-我正往那边去  -在哪儿
- I'm heading there now. - Where is it?
纽约公共图书馆
The New York Public Library.
当然是图书馆  太有你的范儿了  哈罗德
Of course, it's a library. That's so you, Harold.
它会打哪部电话呢
Which phone is it gonna call?
那部
It's that one.
看来德西玛先到了一步
Looks like Decima got there first.
德西玛收到了消息  但他们接不到来电
Decima got the memo, but they'll never get the call.
接线盒在那儿  哈罗德
That's the junction box, Harold.
接下来请交给我吧
I'll take it over there, please.
小心你所期望的  格罗夫斯小姐
Careful what you wish for, Ms. Groves.
你所寻求的那种交流
This communion that you're seeking,
可能和你想象中不同
it may not be what you think.
重点不在我  而在拯救机器
This isn't about me. It's about saving the machine,
让它摆脱德西玛  摆脱你对它的所作所为
not just from Decima, but from what you did to it.
电话响时  我会去接
When that phone rings, I'm going to answer it,
然后你我联手  一起找到机器
and together, you and I are going to find the machine
放它自由
and finally set it free.
卡特警探  我是艾德・索利斯  内务部的
Detective Carter? Ed Solis, IAB.
我知道程序
I know the drill.
向内务部做详细汇报  正确开枪也要
Full debrief with Internal Affairs, even on a good shoot.
正确开枪  你这么以为的吗
Good shoot? That what you call this?
卡特  你说你看见对方亮枪
Carter, I mean, you said you saw a gun,
我相信你  但现场没有枪
and I believe you, but there isn't one there.
约翰天涯海角地追你真是好有爱
It's so adorable how John follows you around like that.
我也想有只宠物
I wish I had a pet.
看来你得找只新的了
Looks like you're gonna need a new one.
感谢帮忙
Thank you for the help.
感觉你能应付
Looked like you had it under control.
希望你带足子弹了  肖
Hope you brought extra rounds, Shaw,
因为后面还有一大波人
'cause we got a lot more guys on the way.
快点  哈罗德  将近午夜了
Come on, Harold, it's almost midnight.
未来要启程了
The future begins
三  二
in three...two...
系统崩溃
启动系统关闭
[ ! ] : . / 动作  系统  重启
[ ! ] : . / 启动除错模式
寻找管理员
当然
Absolutely.
消息来自
芬奇
为你  约翰
我明白
I understand.
来吧  哈罗德
Come on, Harold.
好戏开场了
The fun's just getting started.
你  能  听见  我吗
Can... you... hear... me?